<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: google | zzamboni.org]]></title>
  <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/categories/google/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-05T21:51:03-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://zzamboni.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Diego Zamboni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Scribe-generated prose (aka "Google Scribe channels Kanye West")]]></title>
    <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/google-scribe-generated-prose"/>
    <updated>2010-09-07T17:21:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/google-scribe-generated-prose</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google has launched a new labs project called <a href="http://scribe.googlelabs.com/">Google Scribe</a>, which essentially provides an auto-completion service. You type, it autocompletes. The following text was generated by typing a single space, and from then on simply accepting the default suggestions (pressing "Enter" every time the suggestion popup appeared). I had to stop at some point, but it seems like a good source of mindless entertainment. Also, the result varies depending on the initial seed word you provide, and also on whether you just accept blindly (Enter) or type spaces at certain places. These results also provide some insight into the training texts that were used ("I'ma let you finish...")</p>


<blockquote class="posterous_medium_quote"><em> There are no comments for this user yet and can not believe that there is anything you would not believe how much I loved them all and I'ma let you finish but Beyonce had one of these days I'll bet your life on the road today and they are nothing but another form of therapy for these patients.</em></blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated server and service setup]]></title>
    <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/updated-server-and-service-setup"/>
    <updated>2010-08-16T14:58:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/updated-server-and-service-setup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(a friend asked me about my online setup, and I wrote the text below. Then I realized it would also make an interesting blog post, and I just copied and pasted it, with minimal editing, into an email to posterous. This is why I love posterous, it makes posting so easy) </p>


<p></p>


<p> For my setup, I have a hodgepodge of stuff all aggregated under the <a href="http://zzamboni.org/">zzamboni.org</a> domain. I wrote a blog post about my setup some time ago: <a href="http://blog.zzamboni.org/server-less-does-not-mean-service-less">http://blog.zzamboni.org/server-less-does-not-mean-service-less</a> <p></p> Since then, the main things that have changed is that now my static content (e.g. <a href="http://zzamboni.org/brt/">http://zzamboni.org/brt/</a>) is also served by <a href="http://github.com/">github</a>, instead of Google AppEngine + drydrop. Github used to offer hosting of custom domains only for paid accounts, but now it's available to free accounts as well, so I decided to simplify the setup and host them directly on github. I also just moved the grabcartoons web page to github as well (<a href="http://zzamboni.org/grabcartoons/">http://zzamboni.org/grabcartoons/</a>). So now I have: <p></p> <a href="http://zzamboni.org/">http://zzamboni.org/</a> and <a href="http://zzamboni.org/brt/">http://zzamboni.org/brt/</a> hosted by github from my zzamboni.github.com repository. <br><a href="http://zzamboni.org/grabcartoons/">http://zzamboni.org/grabcartoons/</a> hosted by github from the grabcartoons repository. <br><a href="http://zzamboni.org/things2thl/">http://zzamboni.org/things2thl/</a> hosted by github from the things2thl repository. <br><a href="http://blog.zzamboni.org/">http://blog.zzamboni.org/</a> and <a href="http://posterous.zzamboni.org//">http://posterous.zzamboni.org//</a> (plus some other private blogs) hosted by posterous.com. This is my favorite site for blogging, since it's extremely easy to post by email, plus you can configure it to auto-post content to twitter, flicker, facebook, etc. <br>Email served by Google Apps. <p></p> I'm very happy with <a href="">posterous.com</a> and <a href="http://github.com/">github.com</a>. They are my two favorite services these days.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
