<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mac | zzamboni.org]]></title>
  <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/categories/mac/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-05T21:51:03-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://zzamboni.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Diego Zamboni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HowTo: Changing the available display formats for Evernote's "Insert Date" command]]></title>
    <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/howto-changing-the-available-display-formats"/>
    <updated>2012-11-13T23:00:30-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/howto-changing-the-available-display-formats</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Evernote introduced some time ago an "Insert Date" keyboard shortcut, which is very handy. However, the options for the format of the inserted date seemed limited (only four options). I finally learned how this works, and how to change it on the Mac. The formats offered are those that are configured in the "Languages &amp; Text" preferences panel. If you go to "Region" and then click the "Customize button" in the Dates part of the panel, you will see and be able to customize the formats for short, medium, long and full date representations. Those are the options that are offered to you by Evernote. Just change them to whatever you want, and they will be available for selection. What I specifically wanted to do was to use the YYYY-MM-DD format, so I changed it to the following:<p></p></p>

<div>
<div class="p_embed p_image_embed">
<a href="http://zzamboni.github.com/images/2012/11/13/howto-changing-the-available-display-formats/45777298-System%20Preferences.jpg"><img alt="System_preferences" height="412" src="http://zzamboni.github.com/images/2012/11/13/howto-changing-the-available-display-formats/45777298-System%20Preferences.jpg" width="500"></a>
</div>
</div>


<p></p>


<div>I had to restart Evernote for it to recognize the change, but afterward the new formats were available.</div>


<p></p>


<div>Tip of the hat to Martin Maiers in the Evernote forums, who explained this technique: <a href="http://discussion.evernote.com/topic/29812-insert-date-formats-please-add-iso-8601/#entry160872">http://discussion.evernote.com/topic/29812-insert-date-formats-please-add-iso-8601/#entry160872</a>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remapping Mac modifier keys on Emacs 23.3]]></title>
    <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/remapping-mac-modifier-keys-on-emacs-233"/>
    <updated>2011-11-27T01:47:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/remapping-mac-modifier-keys-on-emacs-233</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just switched from <a href="http://homepage.mac.com/zenitani/emacs-e.html">Carbon Emacs</a> (which is old Emacs 22.x) to <a href="http://vgoulet.act.ulaval.ca/en/emacs/mac">Emacs for OS X Modified</a> on my Mac (which is a Cocoa app, and Emacs 23.3).</p>


<p></p>


<div>One of the unwelcome changes was that the Emacs 'Meta' modifier is now by default mapped to the Option key and not Command as before. But this gave me the opportunity to learn how to map the Mac keyboard modifier keys arbitrarily. I now have the following in my .emacs:</div>


<p></p>


<div>
<div><p>{% gist 1400862  %}</p></div>
</div>


<p></p>


<div>I'm documenting it here just in case someone (or my future self, when I need to redo my configuration at some point) finds it useful.</div>


<p></p>


<div>References: <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/q/2738660">http://stackoverflow.com/q/2738660</a> and <a href="http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/MetaKeyProblems#toc15">http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/MetaKeyProblems#toc15</a>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing cfengine on Mac OS X]]></title>
    <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/installing-cfengine-320b3-on-mac-os-x-107"/>
    <updated>2011-08-05T02:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/installing-cfengine-320b3-on-mac-os-x-107</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://cfengine.com/">Cfengine</a> (tested 3.2.0) installs easily on OS X (tested 10.7), given that it's Unix. One problem I encountered was that it does not compile with the bundled version of Berkeley DB (it recognizes it during configure, but produces compilation errors). The solution is to use some other DB engine. I chose Tokyo Cabinet. Using <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/">homebrew</a>, the process is simple</p>


<p><code>brew install tokyo-cabinet</code></p>


<p>After this, configure --with-tokyocabinet, and then compile and install as usual.</p>


<p>I have submitted a <a href="https://github.com/mxcl/homebrew/pull/6835/files">homebrew formula for cfengine</a>. Once/if it gets approved, you should be able to run <code>brew install cfengine</code> to do all of the above automatically.</p>


<p><strong>Update (2011/09/03): The cfengine homebrew formula has been accepted into the repository! You can now simply run "brew update; brew install cfengine" to get cfengine 3.2.0 installed.</strong></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CopperExport development paused ]]></title>
    <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/copperexport-development-paused"/>
    <updated>2009-12-11T06:44:02-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/copperexport-development-paused</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want to post a short update aimed at users of my iPhoto plugin <a href="http://www.zzamboni.org/brt/code/copperexport/" target="_blank">CopperExport</a>. I have received multiple reports of it failing in recent updates of Snow Leopard, and I have also verified personally that it does not work properly in iPhoto'09.<br><div class="gmail_quote"> <br>Unfortunately, since <a href="http://blog.zzamboni.org/after-the-move" target="_blank">the big move</a>, I find myself without easy access to a Mac for development (I had a Mac at my previous job, and I use Windows at my new job), which pretty much makes fixing these bugs impossible. Until I get a new machine, I will not be able to provide updates to CopperExport. Of course, if any developers out there want to make the appropriate fixes, I will happily accept patches that you submit, and produce a new release myself.<p></p> I apologize to my users for this not-so-happy state, and I want to assure you that as soon as possible, I will resume development. Thank you for your patience and your support, and for the many kind words you have sent me about the plugin itself.<p></p>  </div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
