<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | zzamboni.org]]></title>
  <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-03T00:33:46-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://zzamboni.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Diego Zamboni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New job, new book]]></title>
    <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/new-job-new-book"/>
    <updated>2011-10-19T00:21:07-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/new-job-new-book</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I have two big announcements to make.<p></p></p>

<div>First, as of this week I have a new job, I am now working with <a href="http://cfengine.com/">CFEngine AS</a>, the company that develops and maintains <a href="http://blog.zzamboni.org/tag/cfengine">cfengine</a>. As you know if you read my blog, I am a big fan of cfengine. It is a mature and able tool that provides extreme flexibility and power to system administrators. The company is full of energy and with very interesting projects to make cfengine even better and more popular than it is today. I am very happy to be working with such a talented team. I will be working with the Products and Services group in a variety of roles and projects, about some of which you may be able to read here as well.</div>


<p></p>


<div>Second, and not entirely unrelated, I have been working in the last few months in a book titled <b>Learning CFEngine 3</b>. The book will be published by <a href="http://oreilly.com/">O'Reilly</a>, and should come out sometime early next year. I can't tell you how excited I am to be writing a book for O'Reilly! I have learned so much from O'Reilly books throughout the years, so it is truly an honor to be able to join such select company and to contribute something back to the community. The book is a personal project and not part of my job at CFEngine, although of course working at the mothership makes things much easier in many respects, and my new colleagues are incredibly supportive of this project.</div>


<p></p>


<div>So, that's it for now. Big changes and big projects. I am very busy and very excited, and will keep you posted on both fronts. Thank you for reading!</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Going home]]></title>
    <link href="http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/going-home-49"/>
    <updated>2009-09-07T18:09:05-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zzamboni.github.com/blog/going-home-49</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thirteen years ago, I left Mexico to <a href="http://homes.cerias.purdue.edu/~zamboni/">study a Ph.D.</a> in the U.S. In the meantime, apart from doing that, I <a href="http://fotos.zzamboni.org/displayimage.php?pos=-1596">got married</a>, we <a href="http://www.zurich.ibm.com/~dza/">moved to Switzerland</a>, and we formed a <a href="http://zzamboni.org/brt/2006/02/16/karina-aileen/">beautiful</a> <a href="http://zzamboni.org/brt/2008/09/08/fabiola-aimee/">family</a>. I have learned so many things, I have changed in so many ways. In the words of <a href="http://spaf.cerias.purdue.edu/">my advisor</a>, during one of our very early email exchanges, before I went to Purdue:<p></p></p>

<blockquote class="webkit-indent-blockquote" style="margin: 0 0 0 40px; border: none; padding: 0px;"><i>It isn't so much a leaving as a beginning of something else.  When you return, as you will, it will be with a more wordly viewpoint.  That is both a loss and a gain.</i></blockquote>


<br><div>Now, after all these years, it's time to go home.</div>


<p></p>


<div>At the end of October, we will be moving back to Mexico, to live in the beautiful colonial city of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quer%C3%A9taro,_Quer%C3%A9taro">Queretaro</a>. I will take a very interesting job offer, which I will tell you about at the proper time.</div>


<p></p>


<div>Going back to Mexico is something Susana and I always said we wanted to do eventually, and this seems like the perfect opportunity to actually do it. The girls are still young, we are going back with a solid job offer, and to live in a very nice city. We are truly excited to go back. Still, it's not without some mixed feelings. We have been out of our home country for so long, that I think it's inevitable there will be some reverse culture shock. Switzerland is a beautiful, nice and safe country, which has given us a lot, and I very much like my job here. Still, I jump from joy every time I think we will be back in our home country, every time I realize there won't be any more harsh winters, every time I think I'll be able to eat Mexican food anytime I want, and so many other things I miss. Going back just feels so good!</div>


<p></p>


<div>The next step, of course, is to execute the plan. We are already waist-deep in preparations, planning, searching, and so many other things. It's an exciting time. Stay tuned.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
